[{"id": "60121b0b63c99d48cd169b0a", "question": "The word \"susurrus\" is an example of which literary device?", "answer": "Onomatopoeia -- Some words sound just like their meanings.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd0c4ec223966ae8f88bb", "question": "What is the only Star Wars film in which Harrison Ford receives top billing?", "answer": "\"Star Wars: The Force Awakens\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a5", "question": "Which penguin sex is larger?", "answer": "Males", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0f", "question": "Where does the famous \"running of the bulls\" take place?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf7", "question": "What drink is sometimes called \"La F\u00e9e Verte\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a310", "question": "Which 1979 film featured a space ship named \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a476", "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace8", "question": "Which ancient monument, close to the Pyramids of Giza, is said to have been partly formed by natural elements?", "answer": "The Sphinx", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fa", "question": "Which Andrew Lloyd Webber musical is set in the \"Troubles Of Belfast\"?", "answer": "The Beautiful Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552b23e1c6f9840ba319b", "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef66216ce05a3942286e77", "question": "Who voiced Miss Piggy originally?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3f", "question": "Who was the first European explorer to cross the Arctic Circle?", "answer": "Eric the Red", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb69e25dad637d903c884b", "question": "In which country will you find a peninsula called \"Land\u2019s End\"?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0c", "question": "Who played Khan in \"Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan\"?", "answer": "Ricardo Montalban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0cd", "question": "Which actor was dubbed the \"Muscles from Brussels\"?", "answer": "Jean Claude Van Dam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a77", "question": "Eric Burdon was the front-man of what two 1960's bands?", "answer": "The Animals and War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ee", "question": "Ian Brown fronts which English band?", "answer": "The Stone Roses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339963", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Moe's last name?", "answer": "Szyslak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b58b01dd7bf43be5e7d1", "question": "What was Big Ben renamed to in 2012?", "answer": "Elizabeth Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b323", "question": "Who served as the head of the Soviet Union from 1922 to 1924?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e96127ccba3ffe45786e8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Arachne challenge to a weaving contest?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c8", "question": "What object marks the geographic South Pole?", "answer": "A plaque", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ec7260957c9fcac0ce71981", "question": "Who played Jason Mendoza in the popular TV series, \"The Good Place\"?", "answer": "Manny Jacinto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d1", "question": "With what band did Gloria Estefan sing during the 1980s?", "answer": "Miami Sound Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cf7c877e98cb97778a4e", "question": "Which two rivers flow through the city Charleston, South Carolina?", "answer": "Ashley River and Cooper River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40d", "question": "A bar that appears over a Roman numeral indicates what?", "answer": "To multiply it by 1000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f386fa5fdd6dd25324db", "question": "What company developed and manufactured the Pentium microprocessor?", "answer": "Intel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba2d6874c93a3298b2135", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4543ff048f679a45ab92", "question": "What type of fish is a dangerous delicacy for sushi eaters if not correctly prepared?", "answer": "Blowfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f68", "question": "What volcano did the early Romans believe was the forge of Vulcan, the God of Fire?", "answer": "Mount Etna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baba", "question": "What team did the Green Bay Packers defeat in Super Bowl II?", "answer": "Oakland Raiders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22f", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1985 film \"Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65f", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Mountain State\"?", "answer": "West Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbae7ab0738315b1fb74e26", "question": "What mathematician published \"Elements\" and influenced the study of modern geometry?", "answer": "Euclid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b6", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Aries\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "The ram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed9", "question": "In golf what would you put in your shag bag?", "answer": "Practice balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339147", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339155", "question": "What is a platinum record awarded for?", "answer": "An LP selling a million copies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12f", "question": "What was boxer Arnold Raymond Cream's nickname?", "answer": "Jersey Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a79", "question": "What ethologist told the story of Elsa the lioness in the book \"Born Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015deebfe83fe1f2a824b74", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "England, Ireland, and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfb8a5003d27d341092bbf", "question": "What is the lowest elevation point in the Western Hemisphere?", "answer": "Laguna del Carbon, Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17e", "question": "What is the name of the leading female singer in an opera?", "answer": "Prima donna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea31ebff048f679a45aae6", "question": "What was invented by Chinese astronomer and mathematician Chang Heng?", "answer": "The first seismograph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb9", "question": "Who are Nathan Wind, Vic Colfari, and Sir Stewart Wallace?", "answer": "Characters in the Beastie Boys music video \"Sabotage\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb17", "question": "In late 2005, on what internet dating site did Dr. Phil begin writing an advice column for?", "answer": "Match.com", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8c", "question": "What art word is derived from the French word meaning \"pasting\"?", "answer": "Collage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdd", "question": "What legendary pirate helped defend New Orleans during the War of 1812?", "answer": "Jean Laffite", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f8", "question": "What is the only Canadian province whose borders form a rectangle?", "answer": "Saskatchewan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd4", "question": "What TV show did \"Family Matters\" spin off from?", "answer": "Perfect Strangers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5d", "question": "Who was the Roman God of Love?", "answer": "Cupid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a707", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peach State\"?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590678a9ff9c0647b50a804a", "question": "On what day of the week did January 1, 2016, fall?", "answer": "Friday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c022", "question": "What year was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76b77eec85e375820b2c3", "question": "What is Ireland\u2019s famous Blarney Stone made of?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad92", "question": "What event prevented the lighting of the National Christmas Tree in 1979?", "answer": "The Iran Hostage Crisis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa5", "question": "Whose real-life half sister, Lauren Bowles, played her sister on \"Watching Ellie\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis-Dreyfus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94cfff5ea27d7a1303aed1", "question": "What flavor was the largest scoop of ice cream, according to Guinness Book of World Records?", "answer": "Strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e7", "question": "What does the acronym \"SCTV\" stand for?", "answer": "Second City Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a1e512f2a7826b9b8716", "question": "What was the name given to the French goverment which collaborated with the Nazis?", "answer": "Vichy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb0b67e83c707845b2107", "question": "What was used to fill thermometers before mercury?", "answer": "Brandy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b8", "question": "Who played the alien high commander in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "John Lithgow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6d", "question": "What is the Burmese word for \"Mr.\"?", "answer": "U", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca43", "question": "Sodium Hydroxide is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Lye, or caustic soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78c", "question": "Grits are typically made from what grain?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7a", "question": "In 2008, the city of Milwaukee unveiled a statue honoring what \"Happy Days\" character?", "answer": "Fonzie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3783c0ada16518afdc050", "question": "What was the first Christmas song to focus on Santa Claus?", "answer": "\"Up on the Housetop\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f1", "question": "In which Mediterranean Sea are the Cyclades islands?", "answer": "The Aegean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb5", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Lasky?", "answer": "Grape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8836ce05a3942286d6f", "question": "A silhouette of which player is widely recognized as the inspiration behind the official NBA logo designed in 1969?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c6", "question": "What vitamin is sometimes referred to as the \"sunshine vitamin\"?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90d", "question": "What major river runs through Seoul?", "answer": "Han", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c1a84f032c0db195b477", "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Sir Robert Walpole is considered the first Prime Minister of the UK.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e74606d333868d34d73c", "question": "Where in the Bible is the first Messianic Prophecy mentioned?", "answer": "Genesis 3:15", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecaeb8c790ded87bb38fd8f", "question": "Which major motion film marks Bob Saget's directorial debut?", "answer": "Dirty Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bc", "question": "What does \"Honolulu\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Sheltered harbor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede5006ce05a3942286de4", "question": "What were George Harrison's names in the Traveling Wilburys?", "answer": "Nelson and Spike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca95", "question": "Which disease is also known as Hansen's disease?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff5139aff04d658268c92dd", "question": "The last execution in the Tower of London took place during what war?", "answer": "World War II\u00a0-- Josef Jakobs, a German soldier, was executed by firing squad on August 14, 1941 for espionage.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa38c9c73aa70ea0b70ad5", "question": "Basundi is a dairy product that is popular in which part of the world?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f74a6a9e54d890926f6fc", "question": "It was illegal for women to wear what in 19th century Florence?", "answer": "Buttons", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba72", "question": "What organization for people with high IQs has a name meaning \"mind\" in Latin?", "answer": "Mensa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a97dc61d1b4d384d5d689", "question": "In mythology which giant made of bronze guarded Europa of Crete?", "answer": "Talos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93c216bd93ce3a4e5f6aa", "question": "The bark of which tree is fireproof?", "answer": "Redwoods", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8e", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Cathy Moriarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389df", "question": "Which city sees Pip striving to become a gentleman in \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69b6a20565ad31a57c75e", "question": "What was the last major battle in World War II?", "answer": "Battle of Okinawa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c8", "question": "What is a male donkey called?", "answer": "A jack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c35", "question": "What group of artists was known for its paintings of the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "Hudson River School", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b243", "question": "What king was executed for the excesses of his inquisitional \"Star Chamber\"?", "answer": "Charles I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a493", "question": "Where in Australia did Captain Cook land?", "answer": "Botany Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b840", "question": "In which sport would you be judged on your pike or your jack knife?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339951", "question": "The movie \"Reservoir Dogs\" marked the directorial debut of whom?", "answer": "Quentin Tarentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a8", "question": "Which black widow spider sex is venomous to humans?", "answer": "Female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597743a3284458f1d785442a", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a755", "question": "The Wyandotte Cave is located in which US state?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e49", "question": "What did Ignatz Mouse enjoy throwing at Krazy Kat's head?", "answer": "A brick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a21b", "question": "Craig Phillips was the first winner of the UK version of which TV reality show?", "answer": "Big Brother", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3ea2d38e4e5d4832e6313", "question": "What airline owned the 747 blown up by a terrorist bomb over Lockerbie, Scotland in 1988?", "answer": "PanAm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76c92eec85e375820b2d4", "question": "The ruins of the ancient city of Ephesus are located in what present day country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b911364247bf200fb887", "question": "The fear of flutes is called what?", "answer": "Aulophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b182", "question": "What English captain was the first to visit the Galapagos Islands?", "answer": "Richard Hawkins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a6fb90aac110e4167082", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b280", "question": "In what war did the oak-sided USS Constitution gain its nickname \"Old Ironsides\"?", "answer": "The War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029e1bcad1ec93f27df753", "question": "Who wrote the essay \"A Nice Cup of Tea\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92a", "question": "Where is the Golf Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "St. Augustine, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8f", "question": "What civil rights activist was born Malcolm Little?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323211bf195a31e15d738c", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which Central American country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f1a701dd7bf43be5e806", "question": "What is the name of Niagara Falls' smallest waterfall?", "answer": "Bridal Veil Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25ef516682715b82711cd6", "question": "What year did the Mayflower transport the first English Puritans to the New World?", "answer": "1620", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b434", "question": "How long did the Mau Mau Uprising last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95e", "question": "At what age does a filly become a mare in thoroughbred horse racing?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339061", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Samson Agonistes\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601217f363c99d48cd169aed", "question": "The penny-farthing was a popular type of what?", "answer": "Bicycle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c820", "question": "What military contractor invented the first microwave oven?", "answer": "Raytheon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37c", "question": "Who was the 15th President of the US?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590679e4ff9c0647b50a8052", "question": "What network was primarily responsible for leaking over 11.5 million documents, collectively known as the Panama Papers, on April 3, 2016?", "answer": "The International Consortium of Investigative Journalists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec8", "question": "Mr. Giles French was a character on which US TV show in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Family Affair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b6", "question": "Which English city was actor Stephen Fry born in?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ac", "question": "Where did The Wizard of Oz live?", "answer": "The Emerald City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b67801dd7bf43be5e7dd", "question": "What city drops a giant Peeps chick for the New Year every year?", "answer": "Bethlehem, Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede5766ce05a3942286ded", "question": "What was the first cooking show on television, hosted by James Beard in 1946, called?", "answer": "\"I Love to Eat\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7e", "question": "Franklin D. Roosevelt belonged to which political party?", "answer": "Democratic Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c13", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the seventh plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Storms of fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a4", "question": "What baseball team was known as the \"Gashouse Gang\"?", "answer": "The St. Louis Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392de", "question": "What new wave band recorded the 1978 album titled \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36d", "question": "What valuable product is obtained from the sturgeon?", "answer": "Caviar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e5", "question": "In Judaism, what day of the week is considered a day of rest?", "answer": "Saturday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa0d", "question": "Mount Teide is the highest mountain in which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e5f0d60d274615ecf514532", "question": "What U.S. President's family home was known as the \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\"?", "answer": "John Tyler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8d", "question": "In what year did Babe Ruth reach 500 career home runs?", "answer": "1929", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08768cf631c2414a13b57", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b3d7e662d71a53650fe4", "question": "What is the opening section of an opera called?", "answer": "The overture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57e", "question": "What is the capital of County Kerry, Ireland?", "answer": "Tralee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a850", "question": "Machu Picchu is located in what country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb07", "question": "In physics, what does FTL stand for?", "answer": "Faster than light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b104", "question": "In what city was the first US mint opened?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bf", "question": "How old was Marilyn Monroe when she died?", "answer": "36", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c5c2877e98cb977789b3", "question": "The \"Khyber Pass\" connects what two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f6", "question": "What 1966 science fiction film staring Raquel Welch did Richard Fleischer direct?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c18", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the second plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Frogs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afba", "question": "Who was the last Viceroy to India?", "answer": "Lord Mountbatten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937edc208d98002fdd633cb", "question": "What is the name of Beethoven's third symphony?", "answer": "The Eroica", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60077f9fbd51d85e222ab63e", "question": "What late 19th-century French painter was known for his pictures of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas is acknowledged as the master of drawing human figures in motion. The female ballet dancer became his favorite theme.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5941260abab1e6f9796f1b57", "question": "In Greek mythology, \"Sirens\" were represented as a combination of woman and what animal?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaad", "question": "Autodromo Nazionale Monza is located in which country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae954b574a5ce6b56b8252", "question": "Which river made the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c817877e98cb977789dd", "question": "Which one of the New Seven Wonders of the World is located in Peru?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac3", "question": "Which Renaissance City was severely flooded in November 1966?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede1e36ce05a3942286dc7", "question": "In \"Frosty the Snowman\", which part of Frosty brought him to life?", "answer": "Hat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea34acff048f679a45aaf9", "question": "What unit of measure is used to quantify radioactive element activity?", "answer": "Becqueral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d9abc08b8581f80b092bf", "question": "What big budget game was the subject of monetization controversy and government interference in the fall of 2017?", "answer": "Star Wars Battlefront II", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6b", "question": "How many individual little squares are there on a standard Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "54", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa6f06ce05a3942286ecd", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Jerry Lundegaard was captured by the police in what city?", "answer": "Bismarck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8eb", "question": "What bay is actually the United States' largest tidal estuary?", "answer": "Chesapeake Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a6", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word Brandy?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1ef80145fb2946670738d", "question": "What nut is hidden in Christmas rice pudding in Sweden?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fa", "question": "What are the only two South American countries that do not border Brazil?", "answer": "Chile and Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b318", "question": "What famous leader was assassinated on March 15, 44 BC, the Ides of March?", "answer": "Caesar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029f42cad1ec93f27df75d", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f00", "question": "What street gang rumbles with the Sharks in \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "The Jets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5da854bd1aec824685d88cff", "question": "What two songs did Ferris Bueller sing in the parade scene?", "answer": "\"Danke Schoen\" and \"Twist And Shout\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6f75a9e54d890926f6d1", "question": "What was the capital of Michigan before Lansing?", "answer": "Detroit -- Due to Detroit's proximity to Canada, a perceived threat at the time, Lansing became the state's capital in 1847.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888d", "question": "What did the Seven Dwarfs do for a living?", "answer": "They were miners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52a", "question": "What is both a type of bed and a layer of the rainforest?", "answer": "Canopy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b5", "question": "Which trio released the album \"CrazySexyCool\"?", "answer": "TLC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7534a9e54d890926f706", "question": "In which city will you find Michaelangelo's secret underground drawings?", "answer": "Florence -- In 1530, he stayed in a hidden room beneath the Basilica di San Lorenzo where he continued is art work.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfb", "question": "What is the dot on the letter i named?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3e", "question": "What holiday is celebrated with an aluminum pole, the Airing of Grievances, and Feats of Strength?", "answer": "Festivus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1ad3f6756c9b30ba14f3", "question": "Which Mediterranean island is said to be named after its inhabitants who were skilled in the use of slings?", "answer": "The Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be75", "question": "What NBA star was known for his signature spin move, the Dream Shake?", "answer": "Hakeem Olajuwon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8849ec223966ae8f881e", "question": "Who murders Tommy Williams in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Captain Hadley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c233", "question": "What fashion designer was responsible for the \"New Look\"?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a9", "question": "Trepanation is the practice of drilling holes where?", "answer": "In the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338deb", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"cookie\"?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81fdfd0de9af39e9d469a", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a4", "question": "What screenplay won George Bernard Shaw a 1938 Oscar?", "answer": "Pygmalion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1185a4fea7fe947a22284", "question": "By what name is Lignite often referred to as?", "answer": "Brown coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe3", "question": "On the game of Battleship, how many hits does it take to sink the submarine?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d74", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"There and Back Again\"?", "answer": "The Hobbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89f", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the moon?", "answer": "Selenium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894b", "question": "What is the alphanumeric address of Sherlock Holmes?", "answer": "221B Baker Street", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be42", "question": "What sports team used the Swinging Friar as its team emblem until 1984?", "answer": "The San Diego Padres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25ac4b63e5727cf5a4856", "question": "Who sang the title track to the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\"?", "answer": "Bryan Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f98", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a6", "question": "Which hills divide England And Scotland?", "answer": "Cheviot Hills", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b939", "question": "What is the usual age for a Jewish boy to celebrate his Bar Mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c6", "question": "Which year did Charles J. Guiteau shoot US President James Garfield?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597dddfb77980686f722d17e", "question": "Which century saw the appearance of playing cards?", "answer": "9th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91a", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Bragg?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa5b16ce05a3942286ec4", "question": "In which two films does Clint Eastwood's character sing?", "answer": "Paint Your Wagon and Honkytonk Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb0", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bloody Mary?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a4fe20565ad31a57c7c5", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad14", "question": "In 1952, Albert Einstein was offered the presidency of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea39f9ff048f679a45ab29", "question": "What element is named after the Greek word for green?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba61f874c93a3298b2156", "question": "What defined as \"the ratio between a circle's circumference and its diameter\"?", "answer": "Pi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9d", "question": "What type of mythological creature was tasked with forging thunderbolts for Zeus?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa42273838c5c8a417f22", "question": "What is the most venomous fish in the world.", "answer": "Stonefish (Synanceia) is the most venomous fish.  Its sting can be fatal to humans.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924c", "question": "What do the thieves set out to steal in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs?\"", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd9d5e347d002c297e4cf", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0a", "question": "In 1997, what Oscar winner was replaced by Sarah Ferguson as Weight Watchers' spokesperson?", "answer": "Lynn Redgrave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea4", "question": "Farnsworth Bentley became famous for holding whose umbrellas?", "answer": "Puff Daddy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff25b0531a458464a93c475", "question": "Shito pepper is a commonly used condiment in which part of the world?", "answer": "West Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0eb5469bb8041d07a063", "question": "What is the process of preparing eggs for Caesar salad dressing called?", "answer": "Coddling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c6", "question": "What was the Tuxedo named after?", "answer": "Tuxedo Park, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded35dea2747c8aff16d47", "question": "Which British rock group released a 1990s album called \"Parklife\"?", "answer": "Blur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a8", "question": "What is singer Vanilla Ice's birth name?", "answer": "Robert Matthew Van Winkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc36", "question": "What basketball superstar is nicknamed \"His Airness\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339704", "question": "Which Star Trek character is a big fan of Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Captain Picard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff211b531a458464a93c444", "question": "In \"The Great Gatsby\", what was Jay Gatsby\u2019s given name?", "answer": "James Gatz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339378", "question": "Johann Van der Smut is better known as what?", "answer": "Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdca", "question": "What off-road endurance race is named after the African capital where it usually ends?", "answer": "The Dakar Rally", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3426ce05a3942286f21", "question": "Who is Angelina Jolie's father?", "answer": "Jon Voight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339292", "question": "Which 1989 movie did Weird Al Yankovic starred in and cowrote?", "answer": "UHF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc3", "question": "During what war did hundreds of soldiers spend the winter in Valley Forge?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e97e4ebfabb9c85d8a967", "question": "What is the stage name of Harry Webb?", "answer": "Cliff Richard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a180cad1ec93f27df777", "question": "What are the main ingredients in a Cafe Cubano?", "answer": "Espresso and demerara sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6e", "question": "At what movie's climax does Mookie throw a garbage can through the front window of Sal's Pizzeria?", "answer": "Do the Right Thing's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede0ee6ce05a3942286dbe", "question": "What is the name of the serial killer in the film \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72e", "question": "The Luray Caverns can be found in which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f87", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Dreamgirls\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Hudson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaf3e7e83c707845b20fb", "question": "A \"Tiny Tim\" is a variety of what fruit?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c35", "question": "The Grammy Awards are depicted by what gold plated musical object?", "answer": "The gramophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd3a877e98cb97778a33", "question": "Where is the lowest freshwater lake by altitude in the world?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b814", "question": "What does the Statue of Liberty wear on her feet?", "answer": "Sandals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1e", "question": "What author created the land of Fantastica?", "answer": "Michael Ende", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0f", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Gideon Fell?", "answer": "John Dickson Carr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015fc46fe83fe1f2a824c3f", "question": "The Sykes-Picot agreement of 1916 divided up the Middle East with new boundaries that benefited which two global powers?", "answer": "Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5a", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a89220565ad31a57c7f7", "question": "What city held the world\u2019s first major modern cat show in 1871?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04a", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Austria?", "answer": "Barn Swallow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff7bc0b2b316f4693fb678a", "question": "What is a wainwright?", "answer": "A wainwright, also known as cartwright, is someone who repairs wagons and carts.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e18", "question": "What famed Motown songwriting trio had their first Top Ten hit with \"Heat Wave\"?", "answer": "Holland-Dozier-Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928a", "question": "Which legendary Knight of the Round Table does not appear in the movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Sir Kay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592203e2a4edfd43a087ade4", "question": "The 1999 film adaptation of \"The Green Mile\" starred whom as Paul Edgecomb?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3a63ff048f679a45ab2b", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6f", "question": "What thin cotton fabric used in summer suits takes its name from Persian words for \"milk and sugar\"?", "answer": "Seersucker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a456", "question": "How many provinces are there in Canada?", "answer": "10", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd2", "question": "Who killed Count Rugen?", "answer": "Inigo Montoya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b380", "question": "Which was the first suspension bridge over the River Thames in London?", "answer": "Hammersmith Bridge\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e99b38e4e5d4832e6311", "question": "According to the Bible, who killed more people at his death than in his life?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "arts"}]